Summary

Innovative Sr. UI/UX Designer and Sr. Graphic Designer with over 15 years of experience creating exceptional user-friendly experiences and visual designs. Managing multiple projects simultaneously and meeting tight deadlines. Excellent communication skills, building positive relationships with internal and external customers.

Experience

BenefitHub - UX Designer II, UI/UX Developer II

Tampa, FL - July 2015 - October 2024

- Rendered mockups for BenefitHub's employee discount and perks platform to promote a great user experience
- Generated low & high-fidelity prototypes and wireframes in Adobe XD or Figma to showcase design concepts
- Produced sitemaps, journey maps and user flows with tools like Miro and Visio to structure user experience
- Designed landing pages, web apps, modules, widgets, content pages, and more for ultimate user engagement
- Created logos, vector graphics, icons, ads, product cards and other graphic elements for website enhancement
- Finalized and optimized graphic elements and image assets for handoff to developers for implementation
- Built Adobe libraries and design systems replicating a UI Kit comprised of React.js components such as buttons, modals, input fields, navigation, icons, and style libraries for fonts, color themes, etc. for design consistency
- Developed responsive, mobile-first products with HTML5, CSS3, SASS, and JavaScript to satisfy requirements
- Partnered with front-end and back-end developers for precision and on-time deliverables
- Inspected development projects with cross-browser testing across multiple devices for utmost accuracy
- Complied with WCAG web accessibility standards to ensure designs maintained optimal compatibility
- Collaborated with team members using email, Slack, Teams and Zoom for effective communication
- Utilized Jira and monday.com for product lifecycle management to enhance team coordination
- Managed project timelines, resources and deliverables for multiple UX design initiatives ensuring seamless integration of user research, prototyping, and testing phases

Raymond James Financial - Web Admin Contractor

St. Petersburg, FL - February 2015 - June 2015

- Constructed websites with Sitecore CMS, HTML and CSS producing high conversion rates for financial officers
- Designed logos, graphics and web banners, resulting in creative brand consistency throughout the site
- Refined images with color correction and other adjustments ensuring photos aligned with brand's aesthetics
- Cropped and tailored images for various platforms and devices, ensuring visual appeal for all device sizes
- Optimized images improving page load speed, boosting website's SEO ranking and improving user experience

Sign-Age - Senior Graphic Designer and Web Assistant

Clearwater, FL - August 2011 - June 2014

- Updated company's website content and product image gallery using Firespring CMS to increase engagement
- Designed various signs, banners, indoor/outdoor architectural signs, trade show displays, vehicle wraps, wall murals, POP, and more, while adhering to ADA standards and achieving high customer satisfaction
- Prepared art files for wide-format printing and outsourcing to vendors resulting in ultimate print quality
- Produced 3D-sign technical drawings that assured city, county, and contract approvals needed for construction

Tampa Print Services - Pre-Press Manager and Sr. Graphic Designer

Tampa, FL - April 2003 - March 2011

- Managed the pre-press dept., ensuring the press and digital depts. produced maximum quality products
- Designed logos, brochures, flyers, postcards and other B2B and B2C marketing materials for various clients
- Handled design, pre-press and software updates to stay on schedule and ensure deadlines were met
- Prepared art files for offset, flexo, wide-format and digital printing for optimized printed materials

Freelance & Contract Work - Graphic Designer and UI/UX Designer and Developer

St. Petersburg, FL - January 2010 - December 2022

- Create, update and develop landing pages, forms, content pages, and more for various websites
- Design logos, brochures, postcards, flyers, signs, package designs, album covers, trade show pieces, emails, board game, static and motion graphic social media ads, and more for various clients' marketing initiatives
- Produce motion graphic videos, music lyric videos and social media pieces to boost sales and engagement
- Enhance imagery and optimize photos for print and web to gain excitement of products and attract end users

Education

St. Petersburg College

St. Petersburg, FL

Associate of Science - Computer Science, Web Development

Coding Dojo Web Development Boot Camp

Mountain View, CA

3-month web development training course

Academy of Creative Arts College of Design

Cincinnati, OH

Associate of Arts - Commercial Art

Software

Adobe Creative Cloud | Adobe XD | Adobe Illustrator | Adobe Photoshop | Adobe InDesign | Adobe Audition Adobe After Effects | Adobe Acrobat | Adobe Dreamweaver | Microsoft Office Suite | Google Suite | Visual Studio Visual Studio Code | Figma | Miro | Visio | Sitecore CMS | Firespring CMS | WordPress | Wix |

Skills & Tools

UI/UX Design | Graphic Design | Web Design | Visual Design | Brand Design | Multi-media Design | Pre-Press Vector Art | Prototyping | Wireframing | Art Production | Front-End Development | Mobile-First Development HTML5 | CSS3 | SASS | JavaScript | jQuery | React.js | JSON | Media Queries | GitHub | Azure DevOps | Jira monday.com | Zoom | Slack Teams | A/B Testing | Cross-Browser Testing | UX Research | Copywriting | Copy Editing | Photo Editing | Dieline Drawing | Technical Drawing | Technical Writing | ADA Compliance | WCAG Web Accessibility | Scrum | Agile Waterfall | Project Management | Design Systems